the demand slowed down in the indian
economy has put dominant line of
business under pressure for general
insurance businesses falling automobile
sales mean there are fewer takers for
motor insurance forum bar is standing by
to tell us how the insurance companies
are dealing with the situation it's
something that they may not have faced
in the recent past forum what is it that
they are doing yeah so an image well the
slowdown in the auto sector has impacted
the general insurers as well so the
motor line of business is one of the
dominant line of businesses for the
insurers so the lower or auto sales has
led to the muted premium growth for
these players we also spoke to a few of
the companies and so many players expect
the revival to happen only over the
longer period of time ICICI Rome
Bloomberg sees a revival in the motor
business over the longer term SBI
general expects market demand for motors
to remain tepid for mood another two to
three quarters according to future
generally the government's focused
towards demand growth should pull up the
demand in only couple of years so with
this in the Gunung scenario a lot of
insurance and now focusing more on the
non motor business so even if we look at
the gross direct premium trends for the
industry the non motor segment has
registered a double-digit growth up till
November 2019 while the growth for motor
segments remained the muted at about 9%
now looking at few of the larger players
the largest Lian Yu India Assurance the
net on premium for the player grew the
most in non motor segments for the first
half of this year the highest growth was
seen from the motor business for the
company a while the motor segment saw
Adi growth of 1% for New India Assurance
coming to the largest private player
ICICI Lombard the net on premium again
for the non motor segment registered a
significant growth in comparison to the
motor business so moving on to what the
focus area is for these players now
ICICI Lombard foresees growth from
health property and casualty segments
going forward SBI general
growth in the retail segment to happen
from the health and personal accident
products fine fire and liability
business being the focus in the
corporate segment for the company future
generally has taken special initiatives
for the robust growth in the retail held
business so while the current a while a
lot of players are focusing on the
non-motor business the product makes for
the industry is largely changing now so
the gap between the motor and the non
motor business is narrowing down for the
players now so going forward it is
expected that health insurance will
drive the growth for these insurers so
we spoke to a couple of players and
here's to what they have to say ICICI
Lombard or sees growth in the high in
the health insurance to be higher than
at the motor segment SBI general expects
the company's health portfolio to grow
at about thirty nine percent this fiscal
future generally believes that the
overall health insurance will see a 16
to 17 percent kegger over three to five
years going forward okay forum thanks so
much for putting that into perspective I
think that that point where in which
shows how the growth in the non motor
space has gone up is very interesting
it's it's in part not a conscious
decision but because motor sales have
slowed down
yeah and therefore the companies have
had to go out look at other options for
or my guest yeah and so also one of the
intent of the companies is to create a
balance between the product mix so right
now if you see the motor is one of the
dominant line of businesses so they want
to narrow the gap between the motor and
the non motor businesses so that is also
one of the reasons why they are
aggressively focusing on the non motor
counterpart now
[Music]
you